Register of the D. D. Grimm Papers 1919-1934
Hoover Institution Archives
D. D. Grimm Papers
1919-1934
77002
Grimm, D. D. (David Davidovich), b. 1864
4 manuscript boxes (1.7 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, memoranda, press reports, printed and other material, relating to the Russian emigre community in Finland and other parts of Europe, and to the Russian Civil War.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1977.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Vooruzhennye Sily na IUgie Rossii.; Refugees.; Russians--Finland.; Russians in foreign countries.; Soviet Union.; Russia (Federation); Soviet Union--History--Revolution, 1917-1921--Refugees.; Soviet Union--Social conditions.
Biographical Note
1864 Born, Russia
1899-1910 Professor of law and rector of the Petersburg University
1907-1917 Member of the State Council
1917 Assistant Minister of Education in the Russian Provisional Government
Series Description
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1919-1934 (Boxes 1-2)
  Correspondence arranged alphabetically by last name of correspondent.
- SUBJECT FILE, 1919-1923 (Boxes 2-4)
  Correspondence, notes, memoranda, press reports, reports, newsletters, minutes of meetings, clippings, and printed matter, arranged alphabetically by subject.
- MISCELLANY (Box 4)
  Notes and miscellaneous printed matter.
Container List
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1919-1934
  - Gromyko, Olga and Pavel, 1921 (Box 1)
  - Iudenich, General, 1919
  - Kartashev, Anton Vladimirovich, 1919-1922, 1926, 1932-1934
  - Kirillina, Pavla, 1921-1922
  - Kussonskii, Petr, 1921-1922
  - Nechoroscheff, Nikolai Ivanovich, 1921-1923, 1928, 1931-1933
  - Pototskii, Sergei, 1921-1922
  - Shatilov, General, 1922
  - Vurtsel', Evgenii D., 1928-1929
  - Wrangel, Petr, N., 1921-1922
  - Miscellaneous
  - Miscellaneous (Box 2)
- SUBJECT FILE, 1919-1923
  - Baku oil industry, 1921 (Box 2)
  - Baltic states, excerpts, from the press, 1921-1922
  - Codes
  - Eastern Europe, news bulletins
  - Finland
  - Helsingfors National Center
  - Novaia Russkaia Zhizn' (Helsingfors), 1920-1922
  - Novaia Russkaia Zhizn' (Helsingfors), 1920-1922 (Box 3)
  - Partiia Narodnoi Svobody (People's Freedom Party), Helsingfors, protocols and reports, 1919-1921
  - Poland, 1921
  - Russian Civil War, 1919-1922
    - General
    - Agriculture and national economy
    - Civil rights
    - Commerce
    - Education
    - Government finances
    - Industry
    - North-Western front, 1918-1921
    - Petrograd (Box 4)
    - Press excerpts, 1921
    - Religious freedom
    - Transportation
  - Russian National Union (Russkoe Natsional'noe Ob'edinenie), Paris, congress, June 5, 1921
  - Russian Orthodox Church, 1918-1922
  - Russian refugees in Finland, 1919-1923
  - Russians in foreign countries
  - "Russpress" Russian Telegraph and Press Agency (Warsaw), news bulletins, 1921
  - Vserossiiskii Natsional'nyi Tsentr (All-Russian National Center), Helsingfors, 1920-1922
  - Vurtsel', Evgenii D.
- MISCELLANY
  - Notes and miscellaneous printed matter. (Box 4)